Sanusi Bello



rafiubello4real@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/bello-olaniyan-42626b1b6



+2348027365891, +2348030658291



https://sanbello.vercel.app/

Summary

Full Stack Developer with over 3 years of experience in web development and as a problem solver who loves facing challenges in my work, I'm excited to be at the deployment phase of my career as a web developer. I love to be on a team that questions possibilities. I've previously been a graphics designer, and bring those skills to mγ

UI development on a team. Independently, I've Delivered 150% on sales targets for 3 consecutive years

Experience



MERN Stack Developer

Khristfix Technologies

Jan 2022 - Present

- Frontend development using React Js, HTML5, CSS3
- Backend development using Node Js, MongoDB and Express framework
- · Prepare Technical Design and Specification documents
- · Collaborate with the development team, support, and business on day to day development requestsand support
- Prepare documentation and use case scenarios when required
- · Leads solution designs, documents architecture proposals and creates high-level design Documents
- Lead technical solution sessions to ensure that solutions are complete, scalable and are future-Proof Helps determine coding standards along with the senior development team and ensures consistent adoption by developers
- Conducts code reviews, mentors and coaches the larger team, provides objective feedback toconsultants and development partners to ensure proper execution of projects.

Frontend Developer

FOREMAN ENTERPRISE

Mar 2020 - Jul 2021

- · Participate in the entire application lifecycle, focusing on coding and debugging
- · Write clean code to develop functional web applications
- Troubleshoot and debug applications
- Perform UI tests to optimize performance
- Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications
- Collaborate with Back-end developers to integrate API endpoints
- · Gather and address technical and design requirements
- Provide training and support to internal teams
- · Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Liaise with developers, designers and system administrators to identify new features. Follow emerging technologies

Graphic Designer

Okitech Cyber Café Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

Overseeing all design projects, from conception to delivery
Designing original pieces, including illustrations and infographics
Reviewing junior designers' work to ensure high quality
Oversee all design projects, from conception to delivery
Design original pieces, including illustrations and infographics
Review junior designers' work to ensure high quality
Refine images, fonts and layouts using graphic design software
Apply typography techniques
Generate ideas to portray concepts and advertise products/services
Increase user-friendliness in digital products

Maintain brand consistency throughout all our marketing projects Liaise with marketing and design teams to ensure deadlines are met Stay up-to-date with industry developments and tools

Education



University of Ilorin Bachelor of Science – B.Sc. Physics 2017 - 2021

Licenses & Certifications

- Problem Solving Certificate HackerRank
- Certified CSS Developer HackerRank
- Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- Certificate of Completion Frontend Fundamentals Pirple

Skills

Programming Language

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- (
- Python
- C++
- MatLab
- PHP

Operating System

- Windows
- Linux
- Chrome OS
- AR OS

Databases

SQL

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- SQLite

NoSQL

- MongoDB
- FireBase

Hosting Platform

- Heroku
- Netlify
- Vercel
- Github
- Firebase Hosting

Frameworks / Libraries

- React
- Hooks
- Vue
- GraphQL
- Redux
- Redux-Thunk
- Morgan
- Node JS
- Express
- Axios
- Webflow
- Webpack
- Gulp
- Lodash
- EJS
- Material UI
- Ajax
- Jquery
- Formik
- Styled Components
- Mongoose

Markup Languages

- HTML
- XHTML
- XML

Styling Technologies

- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS
- Sass
- Bulma CSS
- Chakra UI
- Semantic UI

Other Technologies / Skils

- Glt
- CorelDraw
- Jira
- Adobe XD
- Github
- Kanban
- PowerShell
- Bash
- Adobe Photoshop
- Command Prompt
- Microsoft word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Access
- Microsoft Publisher
- Webflow
- Adobe Illustrator

Honors & Awards

Web Design Tutor - NAOSS Apr 2022

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF KASHERE CHAPTER, GOMBE STATE

Programmer of the Year - NAPPS - National Association of Physics Student Feb 2022
University of Ilorin, Kwara State